University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1891-1905
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1891-1905
AZ 427
This Collection contains all of the surviving manuscript materials from the files of the first five Presidents of the University.
Theodore B. Comstock, 1849-1915,; Howard Billman, 1854-1928,; Millard M. Parker, 1849-1928,; Frank Yale Adams, 1867-1919,; Kendric C. Babcock, 1864-1932,
7.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Theodore B. Comstock, 1892-1895
II. Howard Billman, 1895-1897
III. Millard M. Parker, 1897-1901
IV.Frank Yale Adams and Kendric C. Babcock, 1901-1910
Scope and Content Note
This Collection contains all of the surviving manuscript materials from the files of the first five Presidents of the University. There are, obviously and unfortunately, many missing letters and related docuemtns, lost or destroyed before this assortment reached the Library. The user should remain aware of this fact.
There are also other manuscript materials in Special Collections closely related to this collection, chiefly the following:
AZ 406 Papers of the the Agricultural Experiment Station, 1890-1905, 1913-1915. 28 Boxes.
The establishment of both the University of Arizona and the Agricultural Experiment Station was linked in a rather complex and overlapping way. While the University was "established" in 1885 by Legislative action, and ground was broken in 1887 for a building ("Old Main") designated as the School of Mines, it was the prospect of government funds (through the Hatch Act), granted annually to state schools of agriculture, which influenced the Board of Regents to create a sudden School of Agriculture. Frank A. Gulley, the first paid faculty member, was appointed Dean of this unborn School in 1890. In the months preceeding the opening of the University in the autumn of 1891, he selected the faculty, oversaw the completion and furnishing of the first buildings, equipped the laboratory for the Experiment Station, selected sites for the field Stations, and issued the first publications. While not formally designated "President" of the University, he carried out many of the activities and responsibilities of that office, and his papers will be found in the above-mentioned Experiment Station material. His counterpart in the School of Mines, Theodore B. Comstock, employed by Gulley in 1891, later became the fist official President of the University.
Other related collections are:
AZ 34 Letters, reports, and other miscellaneous papers of Howard Judson Hall, professor of English and the fist librarian at the University of Arizona, 1892-1904. 1 box.
AZ 422 Letter-book, University of Arizona Board of Regents, May 1897-June 1901.
In addition are various early financial and student records, as well as the minutes of the Board of Regents.
Comstock, Theo. B. (Theodore Bryant), 1849-1915; Billman, Howard, 1854-1928; Parker, Millard Mayhew, 1849-1928; Adams, Frank Yale, 1867-1919; Babcock, Kendric Charles, 1864-1932; Hall, Howard Judson, 1869-; Hughes, Louis C., 1844-1915 -- Correspondence; Murphy, Nathan Oakes, 1849-1908 -- Correspondence; McCord, Myron H. (Myron Hawley), 1840-1908 -- Correspondence; University of Arizona -- Records and correspondence; University of Arizona -- Faculty; University of Arizona -- History; Arizona Board of Regents; Arizona -- History -- Sources; Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Theodore B. Comstock, 1892-1895
  - Faculty, Staff, Regents, and Governors
    - Faculty, Boggs, Edward M.- Civil & Hydraulic Engineering, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Faculty, Collingwood, Charles B.- Chemistry, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Faculty, Devol, Williams S. - Agriculture, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Faculty, Ferguson, Robert J. - Engineering, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Faculty, Forbes, Robert H. - Chemistry, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Faculty, Foss, W.M. - Music, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Faculty, Goodloe, Meade - Assay, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Faculty, Gulley, Frank A. - Directory, Agricultural Experiment Station, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Faculty, Hall, Howard J. - English, Library, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Faculty, Hoxie, George L. - Physics, Drawing, Mechanics, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Faculty, Hughes, Gertrude - Elocution, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Faculty, Toumey, J.W. - Botany, Entomology, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Faculty, Various, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Barber, Minnie - Stenography
      Benton, L.B. - Horticulture
      Blake, William P. - Geology
      Heberly, J.A. - Chemistry, French
    - Stenographers, Various, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Grounds Foreman/Horticulturist - Mark Walker, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Foreman, Phoenix Agricultural Experiment Station - Charles D. Poston, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Regent, Cheney, George W., 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Regent, Ford, Rochester, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Regent, Freeman, Merrill P., 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Regent, Hilzinger, J.G., 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Regent, Ormsby, John M., 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Regent, Ex-officio, Bruce, C.M. - Secretary of the Territory, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Regent, Ex-officio, Netherton, F.J. - Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Governors, N.O. Murphey, and L.C. Hughes 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Students, Financial Records, President's House
    - Students, Absence Excuses from Parents, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Students, President's Correspondence with Parents, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Students, President's Correspondence with and about Parents, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Students, Mark Walker, Jr., 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Students, John D. Young, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Students, Assembly Programs, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Students, Military Matters, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Students, Miscellaneous Material, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Includes material on disciplinary problems, the University "Hack Line," the "Students Organization," and the Zeckendorf prizes.
    - Commencement, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Micellaneous Presidential Papers, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Includes material regarding class schedules, policies of administration (including the Agricultural Experiment Station), telephones service, and the State Museum.
    - Financial Records, Boarding Department, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Includes advertisement from San Francisco employment firm specializing in Oriental cooks, laundrymen, and house servants.
    - Financial Records, Various, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Includes general appropriations, salaries, student fees, labor and repairs, wood purchases, travel and telegraph expenses, horse care and equipment, and assorted bills from various Tucson establishments.
    - President's House, Plans from the Co-operative Building Plan Association, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - President's House, Robert Mitchell Furniture Co.- Fireplace mantels, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - President's House, Venetian Blinds and Window Screens, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - President's House, Miscellaneous, Furniture and Fixtures, 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Equipment
    - Machinery, Mining, etc. - Fort Scott Foundry & Machine Works Co., Walburn-Swenson Mfg. Co., 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Hugh M. Thompson and others regarding his amalgamator.
    - Machinery, Mining, etc. - Fraser & Chalmers, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Machinery, Mining, etc. - L.M. Rumsey Mfg. Co./Rumsey & Sikemeier Co., 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Machinery, Mining, etc. - Various Dealers, A-Z, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus - H. Landenberger, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Chemical and Scientific Apparatu - James W. Queen & Co./Queen & Co., 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus - E.H. Sargent & Co., 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus - Various Dealers, A-Z, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus - Miscellaneous Dealers, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photographic Supplies, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Office/Classroom Furniture and Supplies, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1892-1895 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Includes football equipment, skeleton models, automatic gate, batteries, electric appliances, elevators, greenhouses, scales, wires and cables.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Advertising UA - Various, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Engineering and Mining Journal
      Engineering Magazine
      C.H. Evans & Co.
      Scientific Publishing Co.
    - Advertising UA - General and Miscellaneous, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Articles by President Comstock - Correspondence regarding, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Engraving, Printing, Diplomas, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Pianos, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Plants, Trees, etc., 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Railroad Matters - Passes, Shipments, etc., 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Water Analysis, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - World's Columbian Exposition: Mineral Exhibit, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mineral Collections, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence regarding the Publication of School of Mines Bulletin no. 3, "Utilization of the Sulphide Ores of Arizona," January-February 1893, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Books and Periodicals - Scientific Publishing Company, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Books and Periodicals - Various Publishers and Dealers, A-Z, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Books and Periodicals - General and Miscellaneous, 1892-1895 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, Atherton, G.W., 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Douglass, Andrew E. and Pickering, W. H., 1894, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Graham, A.A., 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Storment, E.L., President Arizona Territorial Normal School, Tempe, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Tully, Charles H., Principal, Tucson Public Schools, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Requests for Information about UA from Prospective Students, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Requests for Information about UA, General and Miscellaneous, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Requests for Information about UA, Mines and Mining, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Requests for Information about UA, Miscellaneous, Including Arizona as a place to live, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Requests for Bulletins and other Publications, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Requests for UA Catalogs, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Requests for Opinions, 1892-1895 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1892-1895 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Applications for Faculty/Staff Positions, 1892-1895 (Box 6, Folder 3-9)
      Includes applications of John A. Spring to teach various languages, and John A. Roebling (grandson of the Brooklyn Bridge builder) to teach mathematics, mechanics, and physics-both in July 1893.
    - Mining Correspondence, 1892-1895 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with John F. Blandy, ex-territorial geologist; and Charles B. Allaire, regarding a trip to inspect coal mining property.
    - Assay Work, Lot no. 1-399, November 1891-January 1895, 1892-1895 (Box 7, Folder 2-7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence with Bills regarding Assay work, 1892-1895 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series II: Howard Billman, 1895-1897
  - Faculty/Staff, Regents, Governors, Students
    - Faculty, Adams, F. Yale-Ancient and Modern Languages, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Faculty, Barnes, Nathan H.-Civil and Hydraulic Engineering, Irrigation Engineer, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Facutly, Blake, William P. - Geology, Metallurgy, Mining, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Faculty, Boggs, Edward M. - Civil and Hydraulic Engineering, Irrigation Engineer, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Facutly, Devol, William S. - Agriculture, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Facutly, Forbes, Robert H. - Chemistry 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Faculty, Guild, Frank N. - Mineralogy, 1895-1897 (Box 8)
    - Faculty, Rockfellow, John A. - Mathematics, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Faculty, Toumey, J.W. - Botany, Entomology, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Faculty, Woodward, Sherman M. - Physics, Mechanics, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Faculty/Staff, Various, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Foreman, Phoenix Agricultural Experiment Station (N.H. Claflin), 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Board of Regents, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Regent, Ex-officio, Superintendent of Public Instruction: F.J. Netherton, T.E. Dalton, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Governors, L.C. Hughes, Benjamin J. Franklin, M.H. McCord, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Ex-UA President, Theodore B. Comstock, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Students, A - Z, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 17-20)
    - President's Annual Report, 1896; Alumni Association, Constitution, 1897, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      Includes correspondence regarding the Arizona Antiquarian Association; letter of May 3, 1897 from R.E. Peary (discoverer of the North Pole) offering walrus skins to the Museum; letters in December 1896 seeking the flag pole from old Fort Bowie for UA; and correspondence concerning the comet which fell in February 1897.
    - President Billman Personal Correspondence, 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Advertising UA, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Books and Periodicals, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Commencement, 1896, 1897, 1896-1897 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Financial Papers, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Miliatry Matters, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Mining and Assay - includes Mineral collections, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - North Hall - construction and furnishing, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Railroad Matters - chiefly concerning passes for students, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Summer School of Science" at Flagstaff - proposed, 1896, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Office/Classroom Furniture and Supplies - W.S. Pierce, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Office/Classroom Furniture and Supplies - Various and Miscellaneous, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Equipment - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Equipment - Machinery, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Equipment - New Water Tank, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Equipment - Miscellaneous, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Requests - Information about UA - General, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Requests - Information about UA from Prospective Students, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
    - Requests - Catalogs and other Publications, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Requests - Various, 1895-1897 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Applications for Faculty/Staff Positions, 1895-1897 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
      Includes May 17, 1897 applications of C.A. Turrell, University of Nebraska, for a position in modern languages. He was later employed in 1904 and served until 1923.
- Series III: Millard M. Parker, 1897-1901
  Practically all of President M.M. Parker's outgoing correspondence has been lost or destroyed -- only that for 1901 remains in two letter-books. For replies to 1901 letters in Boxes 11, 13-16 the user should consult those letter books in Box 12.
  - Faculty/Staff, Regents, Governors, Letter-Books
    - Facutly, Adams, F. Yale - Language, History, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Facutly, Barker, Katherine K. - Domestic Science, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Facutly, Blake, William P. - Geology, Metallurgy, Mining, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Facutly, Devol, William S. - Agriculture, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Facutly, Forbes, Robert H. - Chemistry, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Faculty, Guild, Frank N. - Mineralogy, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Facutly, Hall, Howard J. - English, Library, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Facutly, Holmes, D.H. - Shopwork, Drawing, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Faculty, La Chance, Imogen - Matron of Dormitory, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Facutly, McClatchie, A.J. - Agriculture, Horticulture, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Facutly, McGauhey, Opal LeBaron - Physical Culture, English, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Facutly, Plimpton, Mary E. - English, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Faculty, Randall, Margaret - English, Elocution, Physical Culture, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Faculty, Rockfellow, John A. - Mathematics, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Facutly, Summers, J.N. - Commerical Subjects, Mathematics, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Faculty, True, Gordon H. - Animal Husbandry, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Faculty, Toumey, J.W. - Acting Director, Experiment Station; Biology, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Faculty, Walker, Mark, Jr. - Chemistry, Assay, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Faculty, Woodward, S.M. - Mathematics, Mechanics, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Faculty/Staff, Various, A-Z, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
    - Board of Regents, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Regents, Ex-officio - Superintendent of Public Instruction: A.P. Shewman, R.L. Long, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Governors, M.H. McCord, N.O. Murphy, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Territorial Auditor, 1897-1901 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Letter Books, January 11 - June 27, 1901; June 27 - September 14, 1901 1897-1901 (Box 12)
  - Students
    - Students, Miscellaneous Items, 1897-1901 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes student petitions and offers to board students.
    - Students, A-R, 1897-1901 (Box 13, Folder 2-11)
    - Students, S-Z, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Applications for Faculty/Staff Positions, General, Includes letter of May 13, 1901 for positon as football coach, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Applications for Faculty/Staff Positions, Teacher placement agencies, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Advertising UA, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Books and Periodicals, General and Miscellaneous, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Books and Periodicals - Various Publishers and Dealers, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Commencement, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Lectures and Recitals, Offers of, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Legislation and Legislators, Includes correspondence regarding the Arizona Antiquarian Association, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Railroad Matters - Southern Pacific Company, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Railroad Matters - Various Companies, 1897-1901 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Equipment - Chemical and Scientific Apparatus, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Includes offer of astronomical equipment from Lewis Swift, Director of Lowe Observatory, California.
    - Equipment - Manual Training and Shop Work, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Equipment - Machinery, Miscellaneous, etc., 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Office/Classroom Supplies, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Furniture; Clock; Flag, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Maintenance and Building Repairs, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - South Hall - Construction and Furnishing, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Military Uniforms and other Clothing, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Pianos and Music, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Printing and Engraving, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Includes an annual report (1900?) by Pres. Parker, and items relating to lighing, insurace, Post Office, mail and delivery services, and the proposed Santa Catalina Forest Reserve.
    - Brown, Herbert - Superintendent, Territorial Prison, Letters relating to material destined for the Territorial Museum. 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - McCrea, S. P. - Principal, Tucson Public Schools, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - McNaughton, James - President, Arizona Territorial Normal School, Tempe, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Mead, Elwood - U.S.D.A., Office of Experiment Station, and Others regarding Irrigation Investigations, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - President Parker Personal Correspondence, 1897-1901 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Requests for Information about UA - General, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Requests for Information about UA from Prospective Students, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - Requests for Information about Tucson and Arizona, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Requests for Catalogs and other Publications, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Requests for Recommendations, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Requests for Students to Act as Agents, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Requests for a Degree from UA - Thomas Grindell, 1897-1898, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Requests for Opinions, Also miscelleneous, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Invitations to Speak, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Requests to Join, Attend, Send Delegates, 1897-1901 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Frank Yale Adams (1901-1903) and Kendric C. Babcock (1903-1910), 1901-1910
  Little material has survived from the Presidencies of Frank Yale Adams and Kendric C. Babcock: a bit of 1901 correspondence, some financial records and bills from 1901-1905, and three letter books (out going correspondence only) from December 10, 1902 to September 22, 1903. Librarian Howard J. Hall served as Acting President, July-August 1903, between the terms of Adams and Babcock.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Students, 1901, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes letter to V. Suarez (Solomonville) from President Adams, requesting that his son Benito be permitted to remain in school - at least until December - as he is needed as the "chief trumpeter" and " one of the best players on the football team." Benito was a member of the first (1899) team.
    - Equipment, Supplies, Furniture, 1901, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, September-December 1901, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Includes Department of Biology Annual Report by J.J. Thornber.
    - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1901-1902, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Maintenance, Food, Supplies, Building Repairs, 1904-1905, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Chiefly bills from Tucson establishment.
    - Chemicals and Scientific Appatatus; Machinery, 1904-1905, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Military Uniforms and other Clothing, 1904-05 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Office Supplies, Books, Bindery, Subscriptions, 1904-1905, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Various and Miscellaneous Bills, 1904-1905, 1901-1910 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Includes advertising, printing, horseshoeing, use of carriages, miscellaneous medical, Western Union Telegraph.
    - Letter-Book, December 10, 1902 to April 20, 1903, F. Yale Adams, 1901-1910 (Box 17)
    - Letter-Book, April 22 to August 12, 1903, F. Yale Adams and Howard J. Hall, Acting-President, 1901-1910 (Box 17)
    - Letter-book, August 12 to September 22, 1903, Howard J. Hall, Acting-President and Kendric C. Babcock, 1901-1910 (Box 17)